Finding Aid for the Alfred H. Bartles Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- DETAILED CONTAINER LIST
  - Series A: Musical compositions—Manuscripts
    - Subseries 1: Single works
      - Subsubseries 3: Vocal works
        - Vocal works. Original works (Box 11)
          - ‘Tell Me the Truth”, May 15, 1980: lead sheet; by Sid Hanvey and Gene MacHowell [pseudonyms of Bryan Lindsay and Alfred H. Bartles]; manuscript with partially realized accompaniment (Box 11, Folder 27)
          - ‘Then”, [n.d.]: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; manuscript (Box 11, Folder 28)
          - “What Will I Do After You”, [n.d.]: lead sheet; by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; manuscript (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Series A: Musical compositions—Manuscripts
    - Subseries 1: Single works
      - Subsubseries 4: Pedagogical works
        - A Pedagogical Approach to Technique on the Violoncello through Scales (Box 12)
          - [Introduction (drafts) and bow angle illustrations], ca. 1990-1997: numerous sketches and corrected drafts (Box 12, Folder 1)
          - “A Pedagogical Approach to Technique on the Violoncello through scales, (in VI Parts): (Parts l-IV)”, copyright 1985: bound photocopy of Parts ll-A, ll-B, lll-A, lll-B, III-C, lll-D, lll-E, lll-F, IV-A, IV-B, IV-C, IV-D, IV-E, IV-F (Box 12, Folder 2)
          - “l-Basic Scale Group”, Oct. 25, 1987: final version; 3 computer-printed copies (Box 12, Folder 3)
          - “l-Basic Scale Group”, 1981-1987: manuscripts and corrected photocopies (Box 12, Folder 4)
          - “IA-Basic Scale Group-vergrößert”, Dec. 2, 1988 [corrected Jul. 21,1989]: masters and partial photocopy (Box 12, Folder 5)
          - “Part ll-Structure of the ‘components’“, Jan. 18, 1986: master (Box 12, Folder 6)
          - “ll-A—ll-C”, Apr. 4, 1988 [corrections from Jul. 14, 2001]: various corrected masters and photocopies; in individual folder; dates drawn from discarded acidic original folder (Box 12, Folder 7)
          - [Edited comb-bound photocopy of Part II], [n.d.]: rejected copy with edits in black and red pen (Box 12, Folder 8)
          - [lll-A—lll-G], [Oct. 10, 1991]: corrected manuscripts; date drawn from discarded acidic original folder (Box 12, Folder 9)
          - “IV-A”, Feb. 21-Mar. 6, 1991: manuscript, some blank pages (Box 12, Folder 10)
          - “V-A”, Nov. 4, 10, 1991: manuscript and unbound photocopies of portion (Box 12, Folder 11)
          - “V-B”, Feb. 14-Apr. 5, 1991: manuscript and unbound photocopy of portion (Box 12, Folder 12)
          - “Vl-A-B”, Jun. 2-6, 1990: manuscript and unbound photocopies, some with edits in red pen from, Feb. 6, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 13)
          - “Vl-I-B”, Oct. 29-31, 1991: manuscript (Box 12, Folder 14)
          - [Incomplete sketch], [n.d.] (Box 12, Folder 15)
        - A Pedagogical Approach to Technique on the Violoncello through Scales (Box 13)
          - [l-Basic Scale Group rejected drafts], [ca. 1988]: manuscripts (Box 13, Folder 1)
          - [IA-Basic Scale Group vergrößert rejected drafts], [ca. 1988]: manuscripts (Box 13, Folder 2)
          - [IA, III, IV, V rejected drafts], [ca. 1985-1991]: manuscripts and photocopies with corrections (Box 13, Folder 3)
          - [Il-A—ll-B rejected drafts], [ca. 1988]: manuscripts (Box 13, Folder 4)
          - [II rejected drafts], [ca. 1985]: manuscripts and photocopies with corrections (Box 13, Folder 5)
          - [Ill-A—lll-G rejected drafts], [ca. 1988]: manuscripts and photocopies with corrections (Box 13, Folder 6)
          - [5 Sketchbooks for Scale Technique], [ca. 1978-1988]: sketches for the Scale Technique; some sketchbooks include theory exercises or drafts for pieces from the Etüden und Vortragsstücke, a Sicilienne, Juliana, Nashville Nashville, unidentified sketches for trumpet and organ, and one unfinished “Beersheba [?Spqt]” (Box 13, Folder 7)
          - [Drafts of charts illustrating the basic bow strokes of cello playing], 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 8)
          - ‘The Pick Ups”, Jan. 18, 1982, [1996?]: manuscripts of cello pick up exercises (Box 13, Folder 9)
            Note: Related texts held in Box 48
          - [Hai Chun Chang pedagogy], ca. 2002-2003: photocopies of various pedagogical etudes and studies, not all from his Pedagogical Approach, presumably for his student Hai Chun Chang (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Series A: Musical compositions—Manuscripts
    - Subseries 2: Sketchbooks
      - Sketchbooks (Box 14)
        - [Various juvenilia], ca. 1940s: fragments of manuscript, spiral-bound notebook with various compositions and chordal exercises (Box 14, Folder 1)
        - [Sketchbook], [n.d.]: various sketches, including incomplete wind quartet and string quartet; spiral-bound (Box 14, Folder 2)
        - “Sketch Book I”, 1953: “Summer ‘53—Oxford”, “Fall ‘53—Athens”; various sketches including orchestration assignments, Piece for Piano, Clarinet & Cello: Opus I, The Stalker, and Music for Br Rd & Per.; spiral-bound (Box 14, Folder 3)
        - “Sketch book II”, 1953: various sketches including Trio for Clarinet, Cello & Piano; spiral-bound (Box 14, Folder 4)
        - “Sketch book no III”, 1953-1955: various sketches including Trio for Clarinet, Piano & Cello, Sonata for Unaccompanied Cello [complete], Sonata for Clarinet and Cello [complete], Structure No II in D \,for Piano Alone [complete], Structure for Cello & Piano No I in G [complete]; spiral-bound (Box 14, Folder 5)
        - “Sketch book No IV”, 1953-1956: various sketches including Trio for Clarinet, Cello & Piano [complete], Solo Trumpet Suite, Theme & Variations, untitled song to words by Siegfried Finzer, Music for Solo Eurythmist, unnamed song; spiral-bound (Box 14, Folder 6)
        - “Sketch Book No V”, ca. 1954: various sketches for Theme & Variations for Orchestra, piano works, and string quartet; spiral-bound (Box 14, Folder 7)
        - “Sketch book VI”, ca. early 1950s: various sketches for Master’s thesis composition; spiral-bound (Box 14, Folder 8)
        - “Sketch Book No VII”, 1954-1955: various sketches for string quartet, Song for Strings, Theme for AI Horsky, For AI & Jo’s band, cello exercises, Piece for Piano, April for Willie Dennis; spiral-bound (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Sketchbooks (Box 15)
        - [Sketchbook], 1955 and some 1974: various sketches including an unnamed string quartet venture, Deep in a Dream of You, Structure in G for Cello & Piano, Structure No. II in D flat for Piano Solo; spiral-bound (Box 15, Folder 1)
        - [Sketchbook], 1955-1956: various sketches including species counterpoint and Schenkerian analysis exercises, Piece in the Style of Brahms [complete], Sonata for Clarinet & Cello in One Movement [complete], unnamed cello/piano piece, unnamed cello solo piece, unnamed string quartet piece, unnamed trumpet/piano piece, incomplete piece for viola (or alto saxophone), cello, and piano, piece for two cellos, piece for cello and piano, cello/piano sonata, string quartet, For Piano [complete]; spiral-bound (Box 15, Folder 2)
        - [Sketchbook], ca. 1958: various sketches including an unnamed string trio, Holy, Holy, Holy, an unnamed string quartet venture, transcriptions of the first Bach Invention for two celli, Walkin’Shoes, I’ll Take Romance; spiral-bound (Box 15, Folder 3)
        - [Sketchbook], ca. 1958: various sketches including One-a-Day Variations for Piano, Rabbit’s Foot, I’ll Take Romance, Adagio in Bach Style, Dixie for Ole Miss Band to Take to [unidentified word] World Fair, All Thru the Night; spiral-bound (Box 15, Folder 4)
        - [Sketchbook] “I”, ca. 1958-1965: various sketches including Trio, op. 9, no. 1/L. van Beethoven, Summertime for 8 cellos, Alone Together, unnamed sketch for cello and piano, Susie, transcription of one movement from Wachet auf/J. S. Bach, You for Mike Petry, Just in You; spiral-bound (Box 15, Folder 5)
        - [Sketchbook] “II”, [1958-1962]: various sketches including Taps Miller, Captain Ahab, ideas for [PConcerto] for trumpet & symphonic band, Lady be Good, unnamed sketches for piano solo, unnamed sketches for string quartet, NSLC Alma Mater, Chewy Lane Theater Jingle, Nobody Smiles Like You [complete], Moon & the Sixpence [complete], Prelude [for cello and piano] [complete], Lounge Lizard; spiral-bound (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Sketchbooks (Box 16)
        - [Sketchbook] “IN”, [ca. 1960-1962]: various sketches including lead sheets for an unidentified work for string trio, incomplete lead sheets for Not Yet, Indian Summer, The March Hare, Does He Love You?, The Lounge Lizard, Alf’s Tune, Kennys Zitz Mark, Snowfall, Zipper Up, Moonlight, Sleigh-Ride on Sno-Shoes, Got My Love, Whippen Us, Autumn Leaves, Jingle for Gotham, piece for cello and piano, pedagogical fingering exercises for cello, and drafts for various letters; spiral-bound (Box 16, Folder 1)
        - [Sketchbook] “Val Valenti”, [ca. early 1960s]: various sketches including lead sheets for various songs not by A. H. Bartles, Time Medely [i.e., Medley] / arr. Alfred Bartles [complete], Medely [i.e., Medley] / arr. A. Bartles [complete], Oliver Medely [i.e., Medley] / arr. Alfred Bartles [complete], Dance Medely [i.e., Medley] / arr. Alfred Bartles [complete], Moon Medely [i.e., Medley] / arr. A. Bartles [complete], Society Medely [i.e., Medley] / arr. A. Bartles [portion]; spiral-bound (Box 16, Folder 2)
        - [Sketchbook] “Val Valenti Orch.”, [ca. early 1960s]: various sketches including lead sheets for various songs not by A. H. Bartles, Sometimes I’m Happy / arr. Alfred H. Bartles, / May Be Wrong / arr. Alfred H. Bartles, Bye Bye Blues / arr. A. Bartles, Mr. Lucky I arr. Alfred Bartles, San Francisco / arr. Alfred Bartles, Taking a Chance on Love I arr. A. Bartles, Und [i.e., 2nd] Chaser / by Tiny Kahn, Alley Cat / arr. Val Valenti and A. Bartles; spiral-bound (Box 16, Folder 3)
        - [Sketchbook] “IV”, ca. 1962-1970: various sketches including Boats at Sea, The Galloping Stallion, All the Things, Etude after Kreutzer 1, The Old Windmill, Aren’t You Glad You’re You, Sonata for Michael, The Sea Gulls and Me, Circus Clown, Fanfare for Wilbur’s Brass, Blues Down Home, Chorale Prelude II Bach: “Sleepers Awake”, Scicilliene [i.e., Sicilienne], The Longest Day, I Wish You Love, Days of Wine & Roses, Dynamite, Alma Mater, My Faith Looks up to Thee, Cheer for Old Vandy, Rock Island, How You Gonna, Banana Boat, Black is the Color, Hallelujah; spiral-bound (Box 16, Folder 4)
        - [Sketchbook] “V”, ca. 1963-1979: various sketches, chiefly pedagogical, including The Gulls and Me, Beside an Indian Campfire, Soldiers on the March, Lightly Row, The Old Windmill, Boats at Sea, Circus Clowns, The Galloping Stallion, Oh My Love, All Thru the Night, Fuchs du hast, Gnomes in a Garden, Dance of the Gnomes, various arranged Christmas carols, Etude after Kreutzer, Suzy, Ceremonial Music for Brass, He is Sleeping, Child Jesus, various lead sheets; spiral-bound (Box 16, Folder 5)
        - [Sketchbook] “VI”, 1963-1964: various sketches including Ballad of Jed Clampett, Dear Hearts & Gentle People, Start of Something Big, untitled song ( You Were in my Dreams a Long Time Ago...), Too Soon Grown Up, No One Told Me the Signs of a Love Gone Astray, March Music City, Elergy [i.e., Elegy] for Solo Tuba & Piano, Theme for a Dramatic Movie, Blues for Paul, Come Ride the Wind with Me, No One Told Me, Jazz Tuba Piece for Harvey Phillips, Balancing Rock, Django -for Stage Band, What Will I Do After You, Roundtop, Read ‘Em and Weep, Augusts, Age After Age, Cabrio Frío, Love’s the Livin’ End, Bags New Groove, [illegible] Rock, [?Ballador] Bolero; spiral-bound (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Sketchbooks (Box 17)
        - [Sketchbook] “VII”, 1964-1965: various sketches including Big Wide Wonderful World, A Little Deeper Shade of Blue, I Looked for Me, Ipanema, Dolly, New York Bound, Fanfare-Short Dynamite & Dixie, Invisible Man, S’il vous plaît, Chaser, Pomp & Circumstance, Zaboch more, I’m Surprised at You, Artistry in Rhythm, Kingdom Comin’, Yellow Rose, Whistler’s Waltz, Dixie & Battle Hymn, Where Do the Dreams Go, She’s So [?Square] [illegible], Appalachian Portrait, unnamed song, If You Mean Love, If You [illegible], Deeper Shade of Blue, Napoli; spiral-bound (Box 17, Folder 1)
        - [Sketchbook] “VIM”, 1965-1968: various sketches including Never Trust a Friend, S’il vous plaît, Whistler’s Waltz, You, Me Forget the World, VU-HalfTime Shows, Halls of Ivy, Brazil, One Note Samba, Ipanema, My Fair Lady Medley, Let’s Play under the Christmas Tree, Blackberry Winter, Crickets & Nighthawks, Untitled Original, End of Perceptions I, Prelude [for piano], Excalibur, Piano Quartet; spiral-bound (Box 17, Folder 2)
        - [Sketchbook] “IX”, 1965-1969: various sketches including unnamed works for keyboard, woodwinds and harp, Lament for flute and violin with bassoon, cello, horn, and clarinet accompaniment, incidental music for And There was Light, Wedding March Processional: opus 10, for the wedding of Elizabeth Buckner Crook & Morton B. Howell III; spiral-bound (Box 17, Folder 3)
        - [Sketchbook] “X”, 1966-1971: various sketches including unnamed work for violin and piano, orchestra, piano solo, H.C. Andersen Christmas Carol, Child Jesu, Theme No. 2 for Del, Piece for Cello Students, Prelude for Cello Unaccompanied, Movie Theme, Scicilliene [i.e., Sicilienne], Bossa Nova for M.H.B., untitled lead sheets, Ballad for Solo Cello and String Orchestra, Blues for Cameron, Cello Sonata, Piano Sonata No. I, untitled piece for jazz trio, A Star Shone Bright; spiral-bound (Box 17, Folder 4)
        - “Counterpoint Studies Book I”, 1967-1980: includes Studies in Counterpoint based on Johann Joseph Fux Gradus ad Parnassum; spiral-bound (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Sketchbooks (Box 18)
        - [Sketchbook] “XI”, ca. 1968-1971: various sketches including Overture for [?Willis], Woodwind Quintet, Cello Concerto, Trumpet Sonata, Lament, Variations & Metamorphosis [for] Woodwind Quintet [complete], Engadine Overture [complete], To Isabel [theme used in The Little Prince], Mountain Rain; spiral-bound (Box 18, Folder 1)
          [1970-1975 sketchbook is located in Box 19 due to size]
        - [Sketchbook], 1972-1974: various sketches including Wind Trio, unnamed keyboard piece, organ and trumpet piece, Courante, Baroque Sonata, theory analyses, unnamed piece; spiral-bound (Box 18, Folder 2)
        - [Sketchbook], 1972-1980: various sketches including unnamed piece for 2 harps, unnamed song without lyrics, Sometimes, Theme from Sometimes, unnamed song without lyrics, Prelude for keyboard instrument, pieces for 2 cellos, unnamed piece for 7 cellos, Tuba Concertino, unnamed song with lyrics; spiral-bound (Box 18, Folder 3)
        - [Sketchbook], ca. 1974-1979: various sketches including works for three cellos [?], lead sheet for Naturally, pedagogical works for cello and piano (Polonaise, Minuet), Nachtakt to Wilder, Etude to M.A.M., Gigue a la tarantelle, Musette, Nanabusch Music, Star Child, Gültig, lead sheet for a bossa nova; spiral-bound, cover missing (Box 18, Folder 4)
        - [Sketchbook], 1975-1987: various sketches including Kling Glöckchen, O du Fröhliche, And Well I Shall Be There, Stille Nacht, O Tannenbaum, Winston’s Piece, Bartok Roumanian Folk Dances, Sonata V-Marcello, Giant Steps; comb-bound (Box 18, Folder 5)
        - [Sketchbook], 1976-1987: various sketches including unnamed piece for [Porchestra], violin solo, Das Echo von [^Steinbruch] for soprano and alto recorders, unnamed piece for cello and piano, unnamed songs, 6 Trumpet Fanfare, others (Box 18, Folder 6)
        - [Sketchbook], 1982-1987: various sketches including Lyric Poem for Violin and Piano, Die Bärenfamilie, pieces for tuba and band, string orchestra, Winter auf Island, Spielende Delphine, By an Indian Campfire, pedagogical exercises, Sicillienne [i.e., Sicilienne], Alexander Löw, Verfolgungs Jagd, Versteck Spiel, Walzer; spiral-bound (Box 18, Folder 7)
        - [Sketchbook], ca. 1983-1987: various sketches including Das Spinnenlied [complete], cello pedagogical pieces, Song of the Lonesome Whale, Violin and Cello Duo, Tubossa, Canon at Prime; spiral-bound (Box 18, Folder 8)
        - [Sketchbook], 1987-1997: various sketches including B [flat] Chávela, pedagogical pieces, Springbrunnen, Blätter im Wind, Rondo-Sonate, Russian Walz, The Twistin’ Rag; spiral-bound (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Sketchbooks (Box 19)
        - [Sketchbook], 1970-1975: various sketches, some complete, including Ricercar for Tuba Alone or in Canon, Ring Out Wild Bells, Chaconne, The Holly and the Ivy, Bonnigheimer Waltzer, Child Jesu, Tuba Sonata, Ballad, Etudes for Pedal Timpani, Jazz Triptytch [i.e., Triptych]; spiral-bound (Box 19, Folder 1)
        - “Etüden und Vortrags Stücke”, Oct.-Nov. 1988: sketches; bound (Box 19, Folder 2)
        - [Sketchbook], 1991-1996: various sketches including Gurti’s Theme, Fishin’, Bartok Sketches for Can. Br. [Canadian Brass], The “It Takes Two to Tango” Tango, Menuet für Judith, Deck the Halls, Bartok Rou. Dances for Band, unnamed hymn; comb-bound (Box 19, Folder 3)
        - [Sketchbook], 1992-2003: various sketches including Duo for Violin and Violoncello, Sonata for Violoncello and Piano; bound (Box 19, Folder 4)
        - [Sketchbook], 1992-1998: various sketches, chiefly pedagogical, but most of this volume is taken up by diary entries and correspondence drafts (Box 19, Folder 5)
        - “Counter point Notebook”, 1993-1999: various sketches including species counterpoint exercises, Three for Two, an unnamed piece for cello and piano, Vivaldi Concerto op. 21, no. 4 for two violins, [?Lesals Lied]; bound (Box 19, Folder 6)
        - [Sketchbook], 1995-1998: various sketches, some complete, including unnamed piece for saxophone and orchestra, Tara’s Theme [string quartet parts], A Christmas Wish, Sing We Now, Byzantine Res. Hymn, Masterpiece Theater [string quartet parts], Music of the Night [string quartet parts], Bossa Nova, Phantom of the Opry [string quartet parts], Pathetique-2nd movt. [string quartet parts], Titanic [string quartet parts], Trumpet Voluntary, The Lord’s Prayer [string quartet parts], Unforgettable [string quartet parts], Now is the Time; spiral-bound (Box 19, Folder 7)
        - [Sketchbook], 1996-2000: various sketches, some complete, including Le Cygne [string quartet parts], Ice Castles [string quartet parts], Somewhere in Time-Theme [string quartet parts], Ave Maria (Bach-Gounod) [string quartet parts], unnamed cello quartet, White Christmas; bound (Box 19, Folder 8)
        - [Sketchbook], 1996-2000: various sketches, including for The Little Prince, Yardbird Suite; bound (Box 19, Folder 9)
        - [Loose sheets], 2000-2001: various unnamed sketches and notes for an autobiography (Box 19, Folder 10)
          Note: Related autobiographical materials in Box 48.
      - Published scores (Box 20)
        - “Appalachian Portrait” / by Alfred H. Bartles. Contemporary Concert Band Series. New York: Sam Fox Publishing Company, ©1965; 4 full scores, condensed score, and parts (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - “Beersheba Neo-Baroque Suite: for Tuba and Violoncello or Tuba and Euphonium/Trombone” / Alfred H. Bartles. T.U.B.A. Series: No. 1. Nashville, Tenn.: Brass Music, Ltd., ©1975; Brass Music: BML-9001; 1 copy (Box 20, Folder 2)
        - “Blue Suit” / by Alf Bartles. Nashville, Tenn.: Robert B. Ferguson Music, ©1964; for jazz ensemble; conductor’s guide and parts (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - “Blues Down Home” / by Alf Bartles. Nashville, Tenn.: Robert B. Ferguson Music, ©1964; conductor’s guide and parts (Box 20, Folder 4)
        - “Elegy: for Bass Trombone and Piano” / Alfred H. Bartles. New York: Sam Fox Publishing Company, ©1970; trombone part and fragment of piano part (Box 20, Folder 5)
        - “From the Notebooks for Anna Magdalena Bach and Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart” / selected and arranged by Alfred H. Bartles. Wien: Universal Edition, ©1990; Universal Edition: UE 18650a (for two cellos), UE 18650 (for cello and piano); 2 copies, one with typed preface (Box 20, Folder 6)
        - “Lady of Spain” / words by Erell Reaves, music by Tolchard Evans, arranged by Alf. Bartles. Fox Manuscript Stage Band Library. New York: Sam Fox Publishing Company, ©1965; for stage band with optional chorus; parts (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Published scores (Box 21)
        - “Lady of Spain” / words by Erell Reaves, music by Tolchard Evans, arranged by Alf. Bartles. New York: Sam Fox Publishing Company, ©1965; for mixed chorus (SATB) with piano accompaniment (Box 21, Folder 1)
        - “Perceptions I” / by J. J. Johnson, adapted for band by Alfred Bartles. MLQ Concert Band Series. New York: MLQ Music, ©1968; 1 full score, condensed score, and parts (Box 21, Folder 2)
        - “Scherzo for Tuba and Wind Ensemble: with Piano Reduction” / by Alfred Bartles. National Brass Solo Series. New York: Sam Fox Publishing Company, ©1970; score and part (Box 21, Folder 3)
        - “Seven Easy Pieces for Beginning Cellists” / by Alfred H. Bartles. [London]: Boosey & Hawkes, ©1967; Boosey & Hawkes: SCB-44, B.S.I. 97; score and part; 2 copies (Box 21, Folder 4)
        - “Seven Easy Pieces for Beginning ‘Cellists” / by Alfred H. Bartles. Nashville, Tenn.: Vanilla Music Publications, copyright 1964; incomplete score (Box 21, Folder 5)
        - “Sonatina: for Trumpet Unaccompanied” / Bartles. Blair Academy Series. Nashville, Tenn.: Brass Press, ©1971; Brass Press: BP 716 (Box 21, Folder 6)
          Note: Manuscript is under the title Night Sonatina
        - “Weihnacht: Cellospiel in Gruppen = Christmas Carols: Easy Arrangements for Two or Three Cellos” / by Alfred H. Bartles. Wien: Universal Edition, A.G., ©1987; Universal Edition: No. 18 703; 1 copy and draft photocopy of introduction (Box 21, Folder 7)
        - “When Canadians Waltz” / by Alfred H. Bartles. Kendor Ensemble Series. Delevan, N.Y.: Kendor Music, ©1995; Kendor Music: 19125; for brass quintet; score and parts (Box 21, Folder 8)
        - “When Tubas Waltz: Scherzo-Trio for Tuba Quartet” / by Alfred H. Bartles. Graded Ensemble Series. Develan, N.Y.: Kendor Music, Inc., ©1976; Kendor Music: 6074C; score and parts (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Reel-to-Reels (Box 14)
        Note: Digital transfers of these reels are contained in Box 26
        - “Joint University Bands”, [n.d.]: Peabody College, Nashville, Tennessee, TA in; does not contain Joint University Bands performance; Track 1, combination of choral rendition of Dixie contrasted with [Alfred and Julia?] playing piano and singing - Track 2, woman’s voice [Martha?] teaching about types of rocks (Box 22, Folder 1)
        - “Demo: ‘Age after Age’“, [n.d.]: by Bryan Lindsay and Alfred Bartles; vocal and piano by Bartles; TA in., monaural (Box 22, Folder 2)
        - ‘The New York Public Library Living Music Concert”, April 24,1969: The Waldorf Chamber Players; on the program is Bartles’s Piano Quartet (1967); includes printed program (Box 22, Folder 3)
        - “Excalibur - an heroic episode for young orchestra”, [n.d.]: Cumberland Orchestra of Sewanee Summer Music Center (16 years old and younger), TA ips, stereophonic 4 track (Box 22, Folder 4)
        - “Excaliber [i.e., Excalibur] - Bartles”, [n.d.]: [Tennessee?] Tech Band (Box 22, Folder 5)
        - “Ohio University Symphonic Band”, Apr. 19, 1970: Gene Thrailkill, conductor-program includes Excalibur arrangement for band, TA ips, % track stereo (Box 22, Folder 6)
        - “Scherzo for Tuba & Symph. Band”, Jan. 6, 1964: U.S. Air Force Band; Harvey Phillips, soloist (Box 22, Folder 7)
        - “Lament, Variations and Metamorphosis”, [n.d.]: for woodwind quintet; Prof. Earnie Harrison, oboe, Louisiana State University Woodwind Quintet, TA ips, stereo (Box 22, Folder 8)